Guide to the Lydia Lunch Papers MSS.590
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I. Photographs and Work Files, 1947-2019; 1976-2000; 24 Linear Feet in 39 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 2 small flat boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 1 record carton, and 2 CD boxes; 10 Gigabytes in 4,489 computer files.
  - The Heart is Deceitful Above All Things -- Filming and Behind the Scenes Images, 2003; cuid30129 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_8)
  - Firefighter Training Images, 2003; cuid30130 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_2)
  - Real Pornography, and Ecstasy at the Mouth of the Abyss Projects -- Press Kit Material, 2006; cuid30131 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_7)
  - CD Design Artwork Files -- Teenage Jesus and the Jerks, and Beirut Slump, 2008; cuid30132 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_1)
  - Lydia Lunch Retrovirus New Zealand Tour Material, 2015; cuid30133 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Lydia Lunch Retrovirus Australian Tour Material, 2018; cuid30134 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Blackout '77 Exhibition with Lunch and Juan Azulay, undated; cuid30135 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Head Gallery Spoken Word Performance including Nick Cave, Thurston Moore, Rowland S Howard, and Others -- Performer List and Scripts, undated; cuid30136 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Photographs -- Headshots of Friends, Unknown Groups of Male Portraits, undated; cuid30137 (Box 39, Folder 9-10)
- Series II. Performance and Studio Recordings, 1962-2015; 1976-1999; 5 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 1 media box, 2 cassette tape boxes; 46.18 Gigabytes in 25 sound and video files.; 49 audiocassettes; 1 film reels; 1 reel; 59 videocassettes (vhs); 2 videocassettes (u-matic); 3 sound cassettes (dat); 1 videocassettes (hi8); 11 videocassettes (minidv); 1 sound discs (minidisc)
  This series contains analog and digital recordings of mostly unreleased live performances and studio sessions of Lydia Lunch, most dating from the mid-1970s to the 2000s. Live performance recordings include shows with Lunch's band Teenage Jesus and the Jerks at CBGBs and Hurrah's, Eight Eyed Spy shows, and also Beirut Slump's first performance, played at the Millenium. This series also includes Lunch's spoken word performances at the Knitting Factory, Bogart's, G's Club, Apolo, and other American and international venues. Some performance recordings include Lunch performing with other artists including Exene Cervenka, Mark Cunningham, Rowland S Howard, Debi Mazar, Hubert Selby Jr., Jerry Stahl, Wanda Coleman, and Emilio Cubeiro. This series also contains recordings of spoken work performances with Emilio Cubeiro and with his band Hot Lunch, often at New York clubs including CBGBs and the Knitting Factory. The series also has a small number of studio recordings of Lunch's songs.
  This series is arranged in chronological order.
  - Henry Miller Concert, 1962; cuid30139 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0092)
  - Hot Lunch Performance with Emilio Cubeiro, 1970s; cuid30140 (Box 51, Reel 590.0068)
  - Live at CBGBs, with DNA, Teenage Jesus and the Jerks, and Alex Chilton, circa 1970s; cuid30141 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0095)
  - Teenage Jesus and the Jerks, Beirut Slump, and DNA, circa 1970s; cuid30142 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0096)
  - Beirut Slump -- 1st Performance at Millennium, circa 1970s; cuid30143 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0097)
  - Hot Lunch with Emilio Cubeiro, Stan, Mener, Paul, 1977-01-19; cuid30144 (Box 51, Reel 590.0069)
  - Teenage Jesus and the Jerks -- Live, 1977; cuid30145 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0093)
  - Guerrieres Talks. Vivienne Dick Films, 1978; cuid30146 (Box 52, Video 590.0001)
  - Rome '78, and She Had Her Gun Already, 1978; cuid30147 (Box 52, Video 590.0002)
  - Teenage Jesus and the Jerks Live at Hurrahs, Max's, and Eight Eyed Spy TR3, 1979-05-31; cuid30148 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0094)
  - Emilio Cubeiro San Francisco Performance, 1980-02-01; cuid30149 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0098)
  - Jeanie, Peter Sheene, and Emilio Cubeiro, 1980-1981; cuid30150 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0099)
  - Swelter. Lydia and Unknown, San Francisco, November 1983; cuid30151 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0100)
  - Lydia Lunch, 2nd Set, Toronto, 1984-08-10; cuid30152 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0101)
  - Bratley, 1986-02-03; cuid30153 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0102)
  - Marty Nation -- Excerpt from Diaries of the Sexually Insane, 1986-03-06; cuid30154 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0103)
  - Lydia Lunch and Karen Finley at Club DV8 in San Francisco, 1986-06-26; cuid30155 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0104)
  - Hubert Selby Jr., August 1987; cuid30156 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0106)
  - Martin Nation, 1987-08-01; cuid30157 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0105)
  - Emilio Cubeiro. "Death of an Asshole". Performed at The Kitchen "Carnival of Sleaze" and Cubeiro Interview on Cable, 1988-02-20; cuid30158 (Box 51, Video 590.0067, Box 52, Video 590.0032)
  - Lydia Lunch Live at Stonybrook, Albany, 1988-03-13; cuid30159 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0107)
  - Lydia Lunch at Pyramid Arts Center, 1988-04-23; cuid30160 (Box 52, Video 590.0003)
  - "Conspiracy of Women" Performance -- Lydia Lunch at Powerhaus, London, 1989-09-20; cuid30161 (Box 52, Video 590.0004)
  - Emilio Cubeiro Live at Knitting Factory, NYC, 1989-11-07; cuid30162 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0108)
  - Fucking Christmas -- Lydia Lunch Spoken Word Performance, 1989-11-15; cuid30163 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_20)
  - Lydia Lunch and Nick Cave with Die Haut, Live in Brazil, 1989; cuid30164 (Box 52, Video 590.0005)
  - The Devil in the Bottle, Knitting Factory, 1990-02-06; cuid30165 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0109)
  - Lydia Lunch, Package. Lunch at Bogart's; Wanda Coleman at Breakaway, 1990-02-16, 1990-02-23; cuid30166 (Box 52, Video 590.0006)
  - Lydia Lunch at Knitting Factory, May 1990; cuid30167 (Box 52, Video 590.0007)
  - Lydia Lunch at Knitting Factory (1990) and the Kitchen (1991), May 1990 and January 1991; cuid30168 (Box 52, Video 590.0008)
  - Second Show at Knitting Factory. Emilio Cubeiro, Johnny Lance, and Lydia Lunch, 1990-05-25; cuid30169 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0110)
  - Emilio Cubeiro Live at Knitting Factory, 1990-05-26; cuid30170 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0111)
  - Butterfly Potion, 1990-06-08; cuid30171 (Box 52, Video 590.0009)
  - Lydia Lunch and Emilio Cubeiro. The Decade Show Performance Series. Schonberg Theater, 1990-06-08; cuid30172 (Box 52, Video 590.0010)
  - Lydia and Denise at Venice Beach, Santa Monica Blvd and "Nation in Pain", October and December 1990; cuid30173 (Box 52, Video 590.0011)
  - Lydia Lunch and Johnny Lance at Knitting Factory, 1991-01-19; cuid30174 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0112)
  - Z'ev and Lydia Lunch in Budapest, 1991-02-01; cuid30175 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0113)
  - Hobiln, Lydia Lunch, Z'ev, Schwarz. Voest / Linz, 1991-09-10; cuid30176 (Box 51, Video 590.0066)
  - "The Beast" Performance -- Lydia Lunch at Pat Hearn Gallery, 1991-09-25; cuid30177 (Box 52, Video 590.0012)
  - "The Book of Death Souls" Performance -- Lydia Lunch and Mark Cunningham at G's Club Communique, Barcelona, 1991-12-17; cuid30178 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0114)
  - "Unearthly Delights" Performance -- Lydia Lunch with Mark Cunningham, Live in Barcelona, 1991-12-17; cuid30179 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0115)
  - "Unearthly Delights" and "Artificial Skin" Performance -- Lydia Lunch with Mark Cunningham, Live in Barcelona, 1991-12-17; cuid30180 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0116)
  - Lydia Lunch Live at G's Club, 1991, 1996, 2004; cuid30181 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_23)
  - "The Beast" Performance -- Lydia Lunch at L.A.C.E. Los Angeles, 1993-03-12; cuid30182 (Box 52, Video 590.0016)
  - San Francisco Art Institute. Instructor: Lydia Lunch, 1993-03-31; cuid30183 (Box 52, Video 590.0017)
  - Lydia Lunch at Knitting Factory, July 1993; cuid30184 (Box 52, Video 590.0013 -- 590.0015)
  - Rowland S Howard and Lydia Lunch, Live in Portsmouth, 1993-07-01; cuid30185 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0117)
  - Lydia Lunch Posse with Emilio Cubeiro, Live at Knitting Factory, NYC, 1993-07-16; cuid30186 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0118, Box 53, Video 590.0033)
  - Exene Cervenka and Lydia Lunch at the Weathered Wall, Seattle, 1994-11-08; cuid30187 (Box 52, Video 590.0019)
  - Lydia Lunch Live at Stony Brook, Albany, 1994-11-10; cuid30188 (Box 52, Video 590.0020)
  - Lydia Lunch, Universal Infiltrators, Live in the U.K., 1994; cuid30189 (Box 52, Video 590.0018)
  - Lydia Lunch and Exene Cervenka, Los Angeles, 1995-02-01; cuid30190 (Box 52, Video 590.0021 -- 590.0022)
  - Lydia Lunch and Exene Cervenka, Sapphire Supper Club, 1995-03-20; cuid30191 (Box 52, Video 590.0023)
  - Teenage Jesus and the Jerks Songs, 1995-05-31; cuid30192 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_10)
  - Teenage Jesus and the Jerks, MX80 Sound, and Lee Ranaldo, Fall 1995; cuid30193 (Box 52, Video 590.0024 -- 590.0025)
  - Lydia Lunch at Rita Dean Gallery, San Diego, 1995-10-01; cuid30194 (Box 52, Video 590.0026)
  - Lydia Lunch and Exene Cervenka, Zootz in Portland, Maine, and Interview with Exene on Radio Free Maine, 1995-12-03; cuid30195 (Box 52, Video 590.0027)
  - Lydia Lunch at Milestone, 1996-03-02; cuid30196 (Box 52, Video 590.0028)
  - Lydia Lunch in Dallas, Texas, 1996-03-19; cuid30197 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0119)
  - Lydia Lunch in Madrid, 1996-05-16; cuid30198 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0120)
  - Foetus Symphony Orchestra with Lunch at Anchorage, "First Exit to Brooklyn", and Lunch at Knitting Factory, "A Short History of Decay", 1996-07-18; cuid30199 (Box 52, Video 590.0029)
  - Lydia Lunch Press Kit Work Samples, 1996; cuid30200 (Box 52, Video 590.0030)
  - Lydia Lunch Press Kit Work Samples, 1996; cuid30201 (Box 52, Video 590.0031)
  - Beth B's Visiting Desire, 1996; cuid30202 (Box 53, Video 590.0034 -- 590.0035)
  - Eight Eyed Spy. CD Reference, 1997-05-01; cuid30203 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_12)
  - Live in LA at Moguls, 1997-05-01; cuid30204 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0121)
  - Ron Athey, Debi Mazar at Moguls, LA, 1997-06-02; cuid30205 (Box 47, Cassette 590.0070)
  - Live Performance, Link Club, Bologna, Italy, 1997-11-14; cuid30285 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_4)
  - Play Genet with Emilio Cubeiro, 1997; cuid30206 (Box 53, Video 590.0038)
  - The Space Between Breaths, J. Handel and L. Lunch at Gallery, 1998-09-01; cuid30207 (Box 53, Video 590.0036)
  - Matri Kamantia, Chicago, 1998-11-10; cuid30208 (Box 53, Video 590.0037)
  - Lydia Lunch, Pesner Lyon, Terry Edwards, Joe Budenholzer, 1998-11-28; cuid30209 (Box 53, Video 590.0039)
  - Debi Mazar at Moguls -- Paradoxia, circa 1998-2000; cuid30210 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0126)
  - Hubert Selby, Jerry Stahl in San Francisco, 1999-04-12; cuid30211 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0122)
  - Lydia Lunch, Stockholm / Nalen. Murdered Song, 2002; cuid30212 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0123)
  - In Our Time of Dying. Lydia Lunch at Kosmopolis, 2002-12-13; cuid30213 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_22)
  - Widowspeak. Lydia Lunch and Pilot 9, 2002; cuid30214 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_13)
  - Lydia Lunch, 2003-04-27; cuid30215 (Box 53, Video 590.0040)
  - Willing Victim -- Live Recordings in Germany, 2003-06-01; cuid30216 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0124 -- 590.0125)
  - Drowning River Phoenix, Narrated by Lydia Lunch, 2003; cuid30217 (Box 53, Video 590.0041)
  - WP 4FG, 2003; cuid30218 (Box 53, Video 590.0042)
  - Lydia Lunch Live Performance in London with James Johnston, Ian White, and Terry Edwards, 2004-04-29; cuid30219 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_21)
  - Lydia Lunch, Set B / T UK, 2004; cuid30220 (Box 47, Cassette 590.0071)
  - Take Note. Music Education, Featuring: Lydia Lunch, 2005-01-28; cuid30221 (Box 53, Video 590.0043)
  - Lydia Lunch at Hemlock, 2005-02-16; cuid30222 (Box 47, Disc 590.0076)
  - Lydia Lunch, C.S.O.A., and Cox 18, 2005-03-11; cuid30223 (Box 53, Video 590.0044)
  - Lydia Lunch Live at Apolo, Barcelona, 2005-03-12; cuid30224 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_17)
  - Sugar Factory -- Cameras 1, 2, and Encore, 2005-09-24; cuid30225 (Box 47, Disc 590.0077 -- 590.0079)
  - Counterculture Hour, Two Shows -- Lydia Lunch, and Lunch with Genesis P-orridge, 2005; cuid30226 (Box 53, Video 590.0045)
  - "Real Pornography" Performance -- Lydia Lunch at L'Antic, Barcelona, 2006-03-29; cuid30227 (Box 47, Disc 590.0080 -- 590.0081)
  - Raw Footage of Lydia Lunch Performance at Leo Koenig Gallery, NYC, 2007-06-28; cuid30228 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_15)
  - Lydia Lunch and Mark Cunningham, 2007-07-20; cuid30229 (Box 47, Disc 590.0082)
  - Pass Like Night Performance -- Lydia Lunch, Mark Cunningham, and Silvia Mestres, 2007-09-29; cuid30230 (Box 47, Disc 590.0083)
  - Lydia, 2007; cuid30231 (Box 47, Disc 590.0084)
  - Lydia Lunch at Corsica Studios, 2008; cuid30232 (Box 47, Disc 590.0086)
  - Lydia Lunch at Heliogàbal, Barcelona, November 2008; cuid30233 (Box 47, Disc 590.0085)
  - MiMi Marseille (Plan Free or Plan Fix), 2009-07-17; cuid30234 (Box 47, Disc 590.0087 -- 590.0088)
  - Big Sexy Noise -- Live in Paris, Main D'Oeuvre, 2009-11-01; cuid30235 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_26)
  - Lydia Lunch and the Big Sexy Noise, Frankfurt, Das Bett, 2009-11-17; cuid30236 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_27)
  - Lydia Lunch, Ghosts of Spain. L'Antic Teatre, Barcelona, 2010-01-30; cuid30237 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_18)
  - Retrovirus. Urge to Kill. Draft, 2015-01-31; cuid30238 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_11)
  - Antic, undated; cuid30239 (Box 47, Disc 590.0089 -- 590.0090)
  - You Are Not Safe, undated; cuid30240 (Box 47, Disc 590.0075)
  - Lydia Lunch -- 13.13, undated; cuid30241 (Box 47, Cassette 590.0072)
  - Untitled Hi-8 Videos, undated; cuid30242 (Box 47, Video 590.0073 -- 590.0074)
  - Ben, undated; cuid30243 (Box 47, Disc 590.0091)
  - Lydia Lunch. Is the Fucking I'm Getting..., undated; cuid30244 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0127)
  - Lunch, Lance, and Wanda Coleman at Knitting Factory, undated; cuid30245 (Box 49, Cassette 590.0128)
  - The Key of Black. Sheene, Emilio Cubeiro, Adams, Perrin, Sheets, undated; cuid30246 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0130)
  - Hot Lunch -- Dizzy Celebrate the Criminals. Emilio Cubeiro, undated; cuid30247 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0129)
  - 13.13, undated; cuid30248 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0131)
  - Marty Nation Speex, undated; cuid30249 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0132)
  - Einsturzende Neubauten and Lydia Lunch, and Roland. The Agony is the Ecstasy, undated; cuid30250 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0133)
  - Torcher, Lydia Lunch and Nels Clive (Demo), undated; cuid30251 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0134)
  - Untitled Tapes, undated; cuid30252 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0135 -- 590.0136)
  - Wanda Coleman and Lydia Lunch at Knitting Factory -- Capital Punishment for Petty Crimes, undated; cuid30253 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0137)
  - Lydia Lunch (Solo Tour) La Poesia Del Rock, undated; cuid30254 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0138)
  - Rowland S Howard and Lydia Lunch, Solos, undated; cuid30255 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0139)
  - Siberia and Lydia Lunch. The Cancer is Finally Become Contagious, undated; cuid30256 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0140)
  - Lydia Lunch, The Right to Revolt, undated; cuid30257 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0141)
  - Willing Victim -- Live Recordings in Germany. Black JuJus and Encores, undated; cuid30258 (Box 50, Cassette 590.0142)
  - Willing Victim. Edits, undated; cuid30259 (Box 53, Video 590.0049)
  - Enrapture with Emilio Cubeiro, undated; cuid30260 (Box 53, Video 590.0046)
  - Rude Hieroglyphics, undated; cuid30261 (Box 53, Video 590.0047)
  - Luna Park. Devils Racetrack. Larry Lewis, undated; cuid30262 (Box 53, Video 590.0048)
  - Road Rant avec Lydia Lunch, undated; cuid30263 (Box 53, Video 590.0050)
  - Lydia Lunch. It Don't Hurt If You Don't Fall, undated; cuid30264 (Box 53, Video 590.0051)
  - Lydia Lunch: TV Interview -- Cutting Edge. Gang of Souls Clip -- Gun is Loaded, undated; cuid30265 (Box 53, Video 590.0052)
  - Lydia Lunch at HotHouse, undated; cuid30266 (Box 53, Video 590.0053)
  - Live in Chicago, undated; cuid30267 (Box 53, Video 590.0054)
  - Wanda Coleman Live at Bogarts L.A.; Lunch, Capital Punishment at Bogarts. Cruel Story of Youth with Wanda at Breakaway, undated; cuid30268 (Box 53, Video 590.0055)
  - Lydia Lunch, undated; cuid30269 (Box 53, Video 590.0056)
  - JK Potter: A Lust for Fumes, undated; cuid30270 (Box 53, Video 590.0057)
  - Salo: The 120 Days of Sodom, undated; cuid30271 (Box 53, Video 590.0058)
  - The Smell of Guilt, undated; cuid30272 (Box 53, Video 590.0059 -- 590.0060)
  - Lost in Music: Girls, Girls, Grrls, undated; cuid30273 (Box 53, Video 590.0061)
  - Jerry Mathers, Lydia, and Exene vs. Nardwuar, undated; cuid30274 (Box 53, Video 590.0062)
  - Lydia Lunch at the Parlor, undated; cuid30275 (Box 53, Video 590.0063)
  - Fetish Ball with JG Thirlwell, undated; cuid30276 (Box 53, Video 590.0064)
  - Blank, Untitled Tape, undated; cuid30277 (Box 53, Video 590.0065)
  - Willing Victim Concert -- Projected Video Images, undated; cuid30278 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_9)
  - Lydia Lunch Spoken Word Performance at Cafe Largo, undated; cuid30279 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_14)
  - CD Master: Artist: Teenage Jesus and the Jerks and Beirut Slump, Title: Shut Up and Bleed, undated; cuid30280 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_16)
  - Live Moscow. Real Pornography. Lydia Lunch, undated; cuid30281 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_19)
  - 13.13 -- Lydia Lunch at G's Club, undated; cuid30282 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_24)
  - Willing Victim-- Lydia Lunch Promotional Videos, Audio, and Catalog Information, undated; cuid30283 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_25)
  - Lydia Lunch Presents: Mary Woronov at Cafe Largo, undated; cuid30284 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_28)
  - Big Sexy Noise Live. Whores on the Dancefloor, undated; cuid30286 (Box Electronic Record, E-records FA_MSS_590_ER_29)